<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coming Together</title>
    <description>A cultural and literary series exploring Polish culture and experience in our community.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 14:33:21 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 14:33:21 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Polish Legends and the Art of Cut-Outs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for an afternoon of Polish folk stories. Each region in Poland brings something different and unique. Just like it’s landscape from meadows through rivers and mountains, the legends of Poland are sweet, scary or simply entertaining. From the tale about “Dragon in Vavel”, “Torun’s Gingerbread” to “Interrupted sound of Krakowski’s trumpet-call”, the audience will travel not only through small, picturesque villages but also through time. We will see some folk art as well as traditional cut outs in paper.Agnieszka Rynkiewicz-Sarrafian is a story teller, fairy tale writer, poet and translator. Sponsored by the Lincolnwood Multi-Cultural Task Force.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/04/07/polish-legends-and-the-art-of-cut-outs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/04/07/polish-legends-and-the-art-of-cut-outs</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Polish Cusine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn the secret to making authentic Polish food as we explore the Polish culture. Join Chef Sam in creating a side dish, a main dish and a dessert. Instructor: Samantha Foreman.For Age: 9+. Registration is through the Skokie Park District starting 2/15/18. Registration code: 111154-01. Register online or at any Skokie Park District facility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/04/06/polish-cusine</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/04/06/polish-cusine</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Celebrating 10 Years of Coming Together: Panel Discussion, Collabortive Pop-up Museum, Collaborative Art Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A beautiful evening of discussion and art with the 10 participating Cultures of Coming Together from 2010-2019 celebrate the 10th anniversary of the program.  Representatives of the Asian Indian, Filipino, Assyrian, Greek, Korean, “Voices of Race”, Latino/Hispanic, Chinese, Muslim American and Polish cultures will discuss their experiences participating in this award winning program, accompanied with pop-up stalls displaying arts and crafts from each culture and a collaborative art project with audience participation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 19:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/04/03/celebrating-10-years-of-coming-together-panel-discussion-collabortive-pop-up-museum-collaborative-art-workshop</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/04/03/celebrating-10-years-of-coming-together-panel-discussion-collabortive-pop-up-museum-collaborative-art-workshop</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pisanka Galore</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn to decorate Easter eggs using the popular wax resist technique. This technique involves applying hot beeswax and staining the egg. Participants will use a bi-color style.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/31/pisanka-galore</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/31/pisanka-galore</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Craft</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Glass Mountain: Tales from Poland by David Walser and illustrated by Jan Pienkowski is an engaging collection of tall tales decorated with colorful paper cutouts. Join us to discuss the tales, learn about Polish wycinanki, and create your own pieces of colorful art. Registration required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/31/book-craft</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/31/book-craft</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Polish Youth Showcase</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us to watch area Polish students put on a talent show showcasing their studies. Students from Ignacy Paderewski, Mikolaj Kopernik and Maria Curie-Sklodowska Polish Schools will take the stage to share about the culture and history of Poland. Crafts and snacks will round out the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 10:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/30/polish-youth-showcase</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/30/polish-youth-showcase</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Film: Ida</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ida won the 2015 Academy Award for Best Foreign Language film, and was the first Polish film to ever win an Oscar.   Ida was directed by Pawel Pawlikowski and written by Pawlikowski and Rebecca Lenkiewicz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/28/film-ida</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/28/film-ida</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Storytime with the Author</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Join author Anna Mycek-Wodecki to read her biographic picture book book Igna_ - The Boy with the Colorful Head - IGNAS Chlopiec z Kolorowa Glowa. This will be an interactive storytime with drawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registration required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/28/storytime-with-the-author</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/28/storytime-with-the-author</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Art Activities Open House at Artorium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Artorium Inc. is a private family-run arts center in Chicago. It is open to everyone ages 5 and up , regardless of any previous art experience. The focus of Artorium is to help students develop their artistic and creative skills through hands on interactions with a multitude of art mediums. Each student is approached with a personalized instruction plan that is customized towards their  age, experience and the ability to handle tools and materials. Students are taught: painting, drawing, sculpture, printmaking, weaving, digital arts and crafts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each student works at their own pace and advances into new techniques and mediums based on their interests and abilities. The center has been established over 10 years ago and is continuing to encourage future artists to fulfill their own aspirations. Each lesson is closely supervised by professionals to ensure a safe and productive learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/26/art-activities-open-house-at-artorium</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/26/art-activities-open-house-at-artorium</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Film: Ida</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ida won the 2015 Academy Award for Best Foreign Language film, and was the first Polish film to ever win an Oscar. Ida was directed by Pawel Pawlikowski and written by Pawlikowski and Rebecca Lenkiewicz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/25/film-ida</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/events/2019/03/25/film-ida</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
